ERIC HUSSMAN

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

503.819.4820 eric.hussmann@gmail.com

erichussmann.com • github.com/erihus • linkedin.com/in/erichussmann

Best described as a T-shaped generalist, I specialize in building web-based software applications applying my knowledge across the technology stack. I use my extensive experience and varied skill set to provide technology solutions and bring value to organizations of all sizes.

My favorite part of this career is building software to help people be their best. I love creating unique solutions and working with teams that are passionate, motivated and full of ideas.

Skills

Frontend

Javascript, ES6, React, Redux, Angular, Backbone, , CSS3, SASS & LESS, CSS-in-JS,

Backend

PHP, Laravel, Python, Flask, Wordpress, Node.js, MySQL, couchDB, Linux, Apache, nginx, REST APIs, Docker, cloud virtualization

Testing

Cypress, Jest, enzyme, mocha, chai, phpunit, behat

Experience

ASML / Software Engineer

November 2018 - Present, HILLSBORO, OR

I joined ASML to be part of an exciting internal software development team with the goal of delivering a custom planning tool for the deployment and maintenance of next generation semiconductor lithography machines.

- Work across the technology stack (React/Redux, Python/Flask, nginx, MySql) to deliver the most value where needed on a small, Agile team
- Work closely with developers and product owners on the team and across the organization to find creative, robust solutions for complex domain requirements.
- Key voice in daily standups and bi-weekly retrospectives and planning. Actively help the team refine their Agile process. Digest and forecast user stories. Coordinate implementation with the development team.
- Responsible for key deliverables in a fast-paced environment to deliver MVP software on an aggressive timeline.

Vogey, Inc / Senior Solutions Architect

JUNE 2015 - December 2018, PORTLAND, OR

Provided technology solutions and full-stack development for Vogey's diverse clientele and project scopes.

- Operated in a partner capacity and technologist to identify client needs and develop technology solutions
- Helped discover and document client business processes and workflows
- Helped grow lines of business by researching solutions for new vertical markets
- Managed all servers and codebases for client technology

M Financial / Technology Solutions Consultant

JUNE 2015 - December 2018, PORTLAND, OR

- As part of Vogey, Inc.'s team embedded at M Financial, involved in the technical implementation of key organization-wide projects.
- Engineered and managed a highly available cloud-based Linux hosting platform to serve websites for over 100 M Financial Member organizations
- Developed a website network platform built on Wordpress to deliver unique and cost-effective websites, with tools to streamline their compliance and support workflows
- Key member in the implementation of M's help-desk software (Zendesk); developed custom workflows and apps for regulatory compliance and books and records.

Harlo Interactive / Lead Developer

MARCH 2012 - JUNE 2015, PORTLAND, OR

- Lead a web development team on a wide variety of projects, including e-commerce, interactive marketing, custom CMS solutions, and API development
- Developed a proprietary CMS on Laravel 5 and Angular. Modular architecture allows fast creation of purpose-built solutions using CLI tool. Documented using gitbook.
- Provided consultation on strategy, timeline forecasting, resource management, and technical delivery.
- Managed dev team operations, including version control, code reviews, and upgrades to our technology stack and build tools.

MediaLab, Inc. / Lead Technical Support Engineer

MARCH 2008 - MAY 2012, PORTLAND, OR

- Provided high level support for issues related to Website building software.
- Developed integrations between helpdesk and CRM software.
- Supported customer education with documentation and webinar demonstrations.

Education

University of California, Santa Cruz / B.A., Modern Literary Studies 2005, SANTA CRUZ, CA